Guide to the Rice University Mary Gibbs Jones College Records, 1956-2014 UA 077
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University Mary Gibbs Jones College Records
1956-2017
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Mary Gibbs Jones College (Rice University)
UA 077
6.75 Linear Feet (13 boxes)
0.39 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0077aip_001 (0.39 GB)
0.027 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0077aip_002 (0.027 GB)
0.76 Megabytes Nearline access: UA0077aip_003 (0.M6 GB)
0.74 Megabytes Nearline access: UA0077aip_004 (0.74 MB)
0.0018 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0077aip_005 (0.0018 GB)
0.083 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0077aip_006 (0.083 GB)
0.157 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0077aip_007 (0.157 GB)
0.348 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0077aip_008 (0.348 GB)
0.13 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0077aip_009 (0.13 GB)
0.17 Gigabytes Nearline access: UA0077aip_010 (0.17 GB)
The collection contains Jones College business material and ephemera such as college cabinet meeting minutes, publications, news clippings and other college documents, such as telephone lists, invitations, freshman information, etc. Jones College was the first dormitory at Rice University (Institute) for women and opened in September 1957.
Historical Sketch
Jones College was the first dormitory at Rice University (Institute) for women and opened in September 1957. The building was made possible by a $1 million grant from Houston Endowment, created by the late Jesse H. Jones and Mrs. Jones. It was named Mary Gibbs Jones College in honor of Mrs. Jones. The College went co-ed in the Fall of 1980.
The original complex, located between the President's residence and Rice Boulevard, consisted of 3 building groups making up a U shape with two four-story dormitory buildings on each side of a court and a dining hall making up the top of the U. Major construction at Rice in 2001 included changes to Jones College. An addition connects Jones North and Jones South on four levels and forms the east end of Jones Quadrangle. The Ground Level was dedicated to the new Jones Commons that replaced the existing facility. A new Kitchen and Servery serves the Martel, Jones and Brown Commons. A new Master's residence was completed in February 2001.
Excerpted from Rice University Construction Web Page.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains Jones College business material and ephemera such as college cabinet meeting minutes, publications, news clippings, and other college documents, such as telephone lists, invitations, freshman information, etc.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Related Material
See Rice University Archives for records of other Rice University residential colleges. Contact Woodson Research Center staff for assistance.
Index Terms
Subjects
Universities and colleges
Document Types
minutes (administrative records); invitations; annual reports; clippings (information artifacts); corrrespondence
Subjects (Persons)
Jones, Mary Gibbs
Subjects (Corporations)
Mary Gibbs Jones College (Rice University); Rice University--residential college system
- Series I: Publications, Lists, & Ephemera, 1956-2013, 36140
  - News clips, 1956-; 36148 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jabberwocky, 1962; 36147 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Roundtable, 1966-1972; 36146 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Telephone lists, 1990-1996; 36145 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Symposia, 36144 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Invitations, 1957-1966, 2007, 2013; 36143 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Freshmen information, 1961-1976; 36142 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Events, n.d.; 36141 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Theatrical (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Jones College Rankings, c. 1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series II: College Cabinet Meeting Minutes, 1962-1995, 36131
  - 1962, Sept. 73-Apr. 76, 36139 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Sept. 76-Apr. 78, 36138 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Aug. 78-Apr. 80, 36137 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Sept. 80-Apr. 82, 36136 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1983, 36135 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Aug. 85-May 86, 36134 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Aug. 86-May 87, 36133 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fall 87-95, 36132 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Series III: Video, 1981-2004, 148189
  - Rosy and Guildy, Act I (8mm Camcorder Tape), February 1999; 148190 (Box 2, Folder -)
  - Rosy and Guildy, Act II (8mm Camcorder Tape), February 1999; 148191 (Box 2, Folder -)
  - Night of Scenes (DVD), November 19, 2004; 148192 (Box 2, Folder -)
  - Beer Bike videos (DVD), 1981, 1986-88, 1990; 184916 (Box 2, Folder -)
- Series IV: Freshman Handbooks and Correspondence, 1966-2011, 160445
  - Correspondence, 1966-1968, undated; 160446 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Jones Newcomers, 1962-1964; 160447 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Jones College Handbook, 1970-1977; 160448 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Handbooks, undated; 160449 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Pikachu GO-Week Book, 2011; 160451 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - O-Week Books, 1992-1995 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Series V: College Cabinet Meeting Minutes, 2010-2011, 160450
  - Minutes, 2010-2011; 160452 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Series VI: Memorabilia, 2010-2018, 160453
  - Shot glass, 2011; 160454 (Box 4)
  - Pikachu GO-Week T-Shirt, 2011; 160455 (Box 4)
  - Jacket, 2011; 160456 (Box 4)
  - Throwback t-shirt, 2011; 163350 (Box 4)
  - Powderpuff jerseys (2), n.d. (Box 4)
  - Soccer jersey, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Medal, n.d. (Box 4)
  - O-Week T-Shirt, 2014 (Box 4)
  - O-Week T-Shirt, 2015 (Box 4)
  - Graduation sash, n.d. (Box 4)
  - Beer Bike T-shirt (2), 2017 (Box 4)
  - O-Week T-shirt, 2016 (Box 4)
  - Floor Olympics T-shirt, 2010 (Box 4)
  - Team Rudawg T-shirt, ca. 2012 (Box 4)
  - O-Week coordinator T-shirt, 2012 (Box 4)
  - Beer Bike T-shirt, 2012 (Box 4)
  - College Night T-shirt, 2012 (Box 4)
  - Beer Bike T-shirt, 2016 (Box 4)
  - Beer Bike cordial glass, 2014 (Box 4)
  - Beer Bike shot glass, 2016 (Box 4)
  - Beer Bike fanny pack, 2014 (Box 4)
  - Beer Bike, 2012 (Box 4)
  - Yellow sunglasses, ca. 2012 (Box 4)
  - Beer Bike koozie, 2016 (Box 4)
  - Jones baseball cap, ca. 2012 (Box 4)
  - O-Week buttons, 2011-2014 (Box 4)
  - Beer Bike bottle opener, 2014 (Box 4)
  - Jones cup and saucer (Box 4)
  - Sam and FrodO-Week T-Shirt, 2017 (Box 4)
  - C3PO-Week T-Shirt, 2018 (Box 4)
- Series VII: Posters, 2011, 160462
  - Red Light District, November 19, 2011; 160463 (Map-drawer 147, Item 14)
    General Note
    Rice University Architectural drawings, oversize manuscript material, maps and photographs, Part 3 of 3 (UA 226-3)
- Series VIII: Student Cards, 1974-1980, 163351
  - B - N, 1974-1980; 163352 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - O - W, 1974-1980; 163353 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Series IX: Centennial Exhibit, 2012, 163627
  This series consists of mounted photographs and other materials used for Jones' Centennial Exhibit. There are more items in Series XIII: Oversized Materials.
  - Construction, 2012; 163628 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Lounge Area, 2012; 163629 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Invitation, 2012; 163630 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Masters, 2012; 163631 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Series X: Documents, 1973-1994, 163632
  - Homecoming, 1973, 1978, n.d.; 163636 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Member lists, 1984/1985; 163637 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1984/1985; 163638 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1990-1994; 163639 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1986, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 8a)
- Series XI: Handbooks, 1967-2013, 163633
  - Jones College Handbook, 1967; 163640 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Jones College Handbook, 1972; 163641 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Jones College Handbook, 1973; 163642 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Getting into Jones, 1978; 163643 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Guide to Survival, 1980; 163644 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Directions, 1981; 163645 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Directions, 1982; 163646 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1983; 163647 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Book for New Students, 1984; 163648 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Let's Go Club Jones, 1985; 163649 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - The Jones Republic, 1986; 163650 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Acapulco Jones, 1987; 163651 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - The Jones Family Album, 1990; 163652 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - The O-Week with an Attitude, 1991; 163653 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Member guide, 1992; 163654 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Jones Addiction, 1993; 163655 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Planet Jones, 1994; 163656 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Freak Show Week, 1997; 163657 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - 00Week, 2000; 163658 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Do Not Pass Go Week, 2001; 163659 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - O Week, Where Art Thou?, 2003; 163660 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Reality Show Week, 2004; 163661 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Harry Potter and the O-Week, 2005; 163662 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Nintendo Wiik, 2007; 163663 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Disco Inferno Week, 2009; 163664 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Would You Like That To Go-Week (2), 2010; 163665 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Super MariO-Week Book, 2012; 173205 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Series XII: Photographs, 1950s-2000s, 163634
  - 1950s, 163666 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - 1960s, 163667 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - 1970s, 163668 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - 1980s, 163669 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - 1990s, 163670 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Jones College had a series of Beer Bike group photographs printed on to foam core. The Woodson Research Center staff scanned, printed, and added them to this file.
  - 2000s, 163671 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - n.d., 163672 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Historian images, 2013/2014; UA0077aip_001; 184915
    Scope and Contents
    JPG images representing student events at Jones College. Images created by the Jones College Historians.
- Series XIII: Oversized Materials, 1990s-2012, 163635
  - Student life photographs, 1990s-2000s; 163673 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Includes a variety of prints, plus circa 250 color slides from 1997 O-Week Scavenger Hunt, Skits, Brunch and Fashion Show, Stadium Rally, and Matriculation.
    - 1997 O-Week images donated by Kaslow
  - Centennial Exhibit Beer Bike photograph, 2012; 163674 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Centennial Exhibit newsclipping, 2012; 163675 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Jones building photograph, n.d.; 163676 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Series XIV: Memorabilia, 1977-2014, 173173
  - Beer Bike drawstring backpack, 2013; 173174 (Box 10)
  - Shot glass with crest (2), n.d.; 173175 (Box 10)
  - Beer Bike shot glass, 2012; 173179 (Box 10)
  - The Kegfather shot glass, n.d.; 173180 (Box 10)
  - Beer Bike T-Shirt, 2008; 184859 (Box 10)
  - Guitar HerO-Week T-Shirt, 2008; 173185 (Box 10)
  - Beer Bike T-Shirt, 2009; 173186 (Box 10)
  - Disco InfernO-Week T-Shirt, 2009; 173187 (Box 10)
  - Would You Like That To Go-Week T-Shirt (2), 2010; 173188 (Box 10)
    One of these T-Shirts has been signed by the senior class that matriculated during that O-Week.
  - Floor Olympics T-Shirt, 2010; 173192 (Box 10)
  - Beer Bike T-Shirt, 2010; 184862 (Box 10)
  - Pikachu GO-Week T-Shirt, 2011; 173193 (Box 10)
  - Centennial T-Shirt, 2012; 184863 (Box 10)
  - Beer Bike T-Shirt (2), 2012; 173194 (Box 10)
  - Super MariO-Week T-Shirt (2), 2012; 173195 (Box 10)
  - Beer Bike T-Shirt (2), 2013; 173196 (Box 10)
  - Beer Bike Tank Top, 2013; 184865 (Box 10)
  - Oh, The Places You'll Go-Week T-Shirt (2), 2013; 184864 (Box 10)
  - Floor Olympics Jersey, 2013/2014; 184866 (Box 10)
  - Mickey and PlutO-Week T-Shirt, 2014; 184861 (Box 10)
  - Green Jones College T-Shirt, n.d.; 173197 (Box 10)
  - Jones Farmer Jones tank top, n.d.; 173198 (Box 10)
  - Powderpuff Jersey (2), n.d.; 184860 (Box 10)
  - Powderpuff T-Shirt, n.d.; 173199 (Box 10)
  - Plexiglass chug can created by Geoffrey "Skip" Wise, ca. 1992; 184879 (Box 10)
  - Jones "Fast Women" Powderpuff jersey, circa 1977 (Box 10)
- Series XV: Publications, 1957-2014, 184917
  - Jones College Handbook, 1957; 184919 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Jones College Handbook, 1958; 184920 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Jones College Handbook, 1961; 184921 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Introducing Jones College, ca. 1968; 184922 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - The Role of the Educated Woman Proceedings, January 1963; 184923 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Guide to Survival, 1979; 184924 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Best O-Week Ever Book, 2006; 184925 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Guitar HerO-Week, 2008; 184926 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Advisor Training Manual, 2012; 184927 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Oh, the Places You'll GO-Week book, 2013; 184928 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Mickey and PlutO-Week Book, 2014; 184929 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Artemis and ApollO-Week Book, 2015 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Series XVI: Student Events, 184918
  - Chorus, 1960s; 184930 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Theatre, 1981, 2002, 2003; 184931 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - O-Week (new student photographs), 2008; 184932 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - O-Week (new student photographs), 2009; 184933 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Divisional Advising, 2010; 184934 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Associates Night, 2014; 184935 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Series XVII: Digital Archive, 2009-2019
  - Sub-Series A: Andrew McDermott, 2009-2010
    - Elections Coordinators (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - President Andrew McDermott files
  - Sub-Series B: Eric Friedlander, 2010-2011
    - Elections Coordinators (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - President Eric Friedlander files
  - Sub-Series C: Steven Boswell, 2011-2012
    - Constitution (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Elections Coordinators (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - President Steven Boswell files
  - Sub-Series D: Julian Castro, 2012-2013
    - Constitution (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Elections Coordinators (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - President (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - SA Senator (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Vice President (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - President Julian Castro files
  - Sub-Series E: Connor Hoppe, 2013-2014
    - Awards Night (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Elections Coordinators (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - President (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Vice President (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - President Connor Hoppe files
  - Sub-Series F: Leah Cabrera-Marquez, 2014-2015
    - Appointed Positions (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Parliamentarian (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - President (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - SA Senator (Box 12, Folder 9)
      PNG images of David Leebron. Created by the Jones College SA Senator.
    - Secretaries (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Vice President (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - President Leah Cabrera-Marquez files
  - Sub-Series G: Gerard Portela, 2015-2016
    - President Gerard Portela files
  - Sub-Series H: Chris Sabbagh, 2016-2017
    - President Chris Sabbagh files
  - Sub-Series J: Ranjini Nagaraj, 2018-2019
    - President Ranjini Nagaraj files
- Series XVIII: Governance
  - Hard Alcohol Probation Report, November 28, 2011 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Series XIV: Publications, 2011-2017
  - Pikachu GO-Week book, 2011 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Dorothy and TotO-Week book, 2016 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Sam and FrodO-Week book, 2017 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - C3PO-Week book, 2018 (Box 13, Folder 4)